# Anshul Sonpure

# Associate Staff Engineer

#### **Profile**

QA Engineer with 4.8 yrs of experience in functional, automation, API, and web security expertise testing. My is in Automation(Selenium, TestNG, Cucumber. API Testing(RestAssured, Java). Web-Security Framework), and Testing(OWASP vulnerabilities). I'm looking forward to work on Test Automation Frameworks Development (Web, Mobile, and API).

## **Professional Experience**

### **Associate Staff Engineer**

Nagarro

2022 - present

Performed Functional testing, Regression testing, System testing, Integration testing, GUI testing, and User Acceptance testing.

#### **Software Test Engineer**

Amdocs development centre India

2021 - 2022

Working on User Lifecycle management application.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked on API Testing, focusing on test
- and automation creation maintenance
- Implemented logic towards a robust Rest
- testing process and code clean-up
- · Working with tools like ReadyAPI and Postman for
- testing RESTFul web services
- Validation of JSON response and assertions. Skill's used: API Testing, ReadyAPI, and Postman.

#### Skills

#### Web Automation

Selenium, TestNG, Cucumber, Maven

#### **API Testing**

Rest Assured, Karate Framework, Cucumber

## **Web Security**

**Testing** 

**OWASP Vulnerabilities** 

## **Programming**

Languages

Java, Python, Shell Script

### **Code Management**

Git, Github, Bitbucket

#### **Education**

#### M.Tech

NRI-Institute of Research and Technology 2013 - 2016

#### **Bachelor of Engineering**

NRI-Institute of Research and Technology 2009 - 2013

## **Programmer Analyst**

Cognizant Technologies Solutions

2019 - 2021

1. Worked on Identity and Access Management (IAM)

application.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Worked on Functional and Automation testing

- Involved in the implementation of the Test
- Automation Framework build using UFT and TOSCA
- Demonstrated Web Automation and API testing via
- Rest Assured and Selenium for better execution time
- and better reporting

Skill's used: Manual, Automation testing, UFT, TOSCA,

Rest Assured, Selenium, TestNG, and Cucumber

### **Programmer Analyst**

Cognizant Technologies Solutions

2019 - 2021

2. Worked on a Trading application implemented in a Banking Domain.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked on Functional and Automation testing
- Worked on shell script testing and execution
- Wrote and executed SQL statements to retrieve data
- from the back-end.
- Analyzed Business Requirements, Functional Specs

and designed the requirements in Quality Center.

Skill's used: Manual, Automation testing, Oracle and Sybase DB, SOAPUI.

#### **Declaration**

All the information shared in the resume is correct, and I take full responsibility for its correctness.

Anshul Sonpure Bhopal, 02/11/2022

#### Certificates

## Scrum and Agile

Udemy - June'2020

# Advanced Selenium Webdriver with Java and TestNG

Udemy - September'2020

# Java: Automated API Testing with REST Assured

Linked Learning –Jan 04'2022

## **Projects**

#### **Web Automation Framework**

Maven Project build on Selenium, Java, TestNG and implementing ExtentReport version 5.0.9.

## **API Testing using Rest Assured** □

Repository for all those who want to learn API testing using rest assured.

## API Testing using Karate Framework 🛮

Repository for learning Karate Framework for API Testing.

#### **Login System** 🛮

Implementation of the backend(Node.js) routes with the frontend(EJS-based template).

## Strengths

Leadership | Detail-oriented Multitasking Adaptability Presentation skills | Project management | Keen-Learner